MAXWELL KWARTENG

15955 Frederick Road #2576, Derwood, MD | (240) 515-0374 | maxtheflash007@gmail.com | GitHub: Max-spec007 | MyPortfolio | Open to Relocate

SUMMARY

I am a Full-Stack Software Engineer with experience in React frameworks and mobile-first apps. Working in the healthcare field has given me extensive experience and knowledge with problem-solving techniques, multitasking, and self-learning skills that translate well into the tech industry. After eight years of serving the community, I am excited to connect users and clients through building new projects in tech.

TECH STACKS

FRONT-END: React, TypeScript, Angular, Django, JavaScript, Node, HTML, CSS, JQuery-Ajax, CORS, SaSS, BootStrap

BACK-END: AWS Cloud API, Express API, MongoDB, Mongoose, Heroku API, Node, Hadoop, Java, Python

WORK EXPERIENCE

Front-End Software Engineer

November 2020 - Present

Chanson Music Studios

- ⇒ Creating and testing Javascript applications for the website.
- ⇒ Troubleshooting website issues such as no call to action, no https, broken links, and slow load web speed.
- ⇒ Maintaining and updating the website functions and executions as well as on mobile devices.
- ⇒ Constant communication with staff and supervisors concerning the use and flow of the website.

The Jackson Clinics / Shady Grove Orthopedics / Modern Smiles

August 2015 - March 2020

Exercise Specialist / Administrative Assistant/ Dental Executive Secretary

- ⇒ Educated patients on the proper exercise techniques, educates patient and family members on proper techniques for transitioning from a hospital-based fitness program to a safe and effective home exercise program.
- ⇒ Evaluated the needs of new clients, created choreographed exercise programs and monitored weekly progress.
- ⇒ Assisted patients regarding office protocols, scheduling, insurance benefits, and copayments.
- ⇒ Provided assistance to orthopedic surgeons and physical therapies with patient's support procedures, and restocking of medical supplies.

Montgomery College August 2013 – August 2015

Instructional Lab Coordinator of the Biology & Physics Department

⇒ Coordinated operational activities in a research or instructional laboratory, providing support services to researchers, faculty, students and technicians. Coordinated departmental use of equipment and supplies.

PROJECTS

PC Games App (TypeScript Application)

May 2021 - Present

⇒ An online app that features free games to play on a desktop PC. This app uses TypeScript, Babel, Wepack, Node.js, JavaScript, HTML, along with Yarn.

Sneak Peek App (React Application)

February 2021 – Present

⇒ Sneak Peek is a sneaker catalog app that is for all sneaker enthusiasts alike. This sneaker catalog features some of the World's most popular brands, such as Jordans, Nikes, and Adidas. This app allows the user to search by shoe brands only. Main technology used in this app is React.

Emotions in Motion App (React Application)

November 2020 - Present

⇒ Emotions in Motion is a place for the mind, body, and soul. This is a mental health app that is geared towards inspiring others. Main technology used in this app is React.

EDUCATION

General Assembly Bootcamp *Full-Stack Software Engineer*

Graduated November 2020

University of Missouri-Columbia *Bachelor of Science, Biology (Pre-Medicine)*

Graduated May 2012